<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>TITOLO OPERA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Publication Information</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Information about the source</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#">
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?place_annotation_20250118132126345",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2025-01-18T12:21:26.345Z",
	"dcterms:modified": "2025-01-18T12:21:26.345Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Martinogiordano",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "Martino Giordano"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?place_annotation_20250118132126345#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.6.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?place_annotation_20250118132126345#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p/placeName[2]"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:RealPlace",
		"@id": "https://geonames.org/5279468",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.6.0"
	}
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?place_annotation_20250118132149444",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2025-01-18T12:21:49.444Z",
	"dcterms:modified": "2025-01-18T12:21:49.444Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Martinogiordano",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "Martino Giordano"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?place_annotation_20250118132149444#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.6.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?place_annotation_20250118132149444#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p[2]/placeName"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:RealPlace",
		"@id": "https://geonames.org/3165524",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.6.0"
	}
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?date_annotation_20250118132206947",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2025-01-18T12:22:06.947Z",
	"dcterms:modified": "2025-01-18T12:22:06.947Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Martinogiordano",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "Martino Giordano"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?date_annotation_20250118132206947#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.6.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chrisdag91/Paves-e/main/Testi-13012025/PL_19300112_ChiuminattoAntonio.xml?date_annotation_20250118132206947#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p[2]/date"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "xsd:date",
		"rdf:value": "1930-01-12"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.6.0"
	}
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>Ad <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/120757469/">Antonio Chiuminatto</persName>, <placeName ref="#GreenBay" type="Real">Green Bay</placeName>, <placeName key="Wisconsin Wisconsin United States" ref="https://geonames.org/5279468" type="Real">Wisconsin</placeName>.</p>
			<p>[<placeName key="Turin Piedmont Italy" ref="https://geonames.org/3165524" type="Real">Torino</placeName>,] <date when="1930-01-12">January 12th, 1930</date></p>
			<p/>
			<p>Dear <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/120757469/">Mr Chiuminatto</persName>:</p>
			<p>I'm befuddled, all in a daze, with your titanic kindness. I'm now seeing the world only through a veil of pink sheets, all bristling with slang-phrases which are meddling together, re-echoing and staring at me from everywhere. I've got now I can no more take a pull out of a bottle together with my gang, without thinking I'm going on the grand sneak. And how flip I get sometimes! And how many keen mamas I'm looking after! And how...so on. My whole existence has got a slang drift now. You could almost say I'm a slang-slinger. (Ha!)</p>
			<p>But I must, for the first thing, give utterance to a whole row of thanksgivings for your long-yearned hard-hoped, fast-sent and all-surpassing answer to my criminal letter. Criminal and murderous, I say, was that letter, with all its flippancy and hard-boiled guyness, but you were so widely christian as to ship your hand to the poor sinner hearkening to him.</p>
			<p>I repeat, I'm yet befuddled, all in a daze, with your kindness.</p>
			<p>Certainly, all your explanations are quite well, easy, clear, better than any would have dream'd of (I'm studying them by heart), but, I wonder, whence did you get the time to put them down? And, more, being such a work intended for a fellow you remembered scarsely perhaps? There is something of witchcraft in it. I can only stare at such a sight, bruit aloud your praise, go capering about and... and continue to get the most out of you. I'm sure I'll find no bottom.</p>
			<p>Really, I went capering the day before yesterday on receiving your letter and yesterday on receiving the comments.</p>
			<p>Forewarned by the former, I was already thinking about something wonderful, darby, whizy, and what not, but the latter, when on my desk here, got me flabbergasted.</p>
			<p>All is useful and masterful in your items, and so abundant is the treasure there one is almost dumbfounded, not by lack of clearness but by dint of wealth. I've not to pardon you, as you say, for your shortcomings - certainly you cannot be acquainted with the queerest phrases a writer was contriving, the more so having you got these phrases detached from the context   but rather I must thank and thank again and praise you for your kindness and skillfulness and sound knowledge. Besides, you'll better understand my full satisfaction thinking (the scoundrel!) with what impudent hurry I'm sending you another list.</p>
			<p>But we are agreed - you'll explain and send it only when, and if, you'll be able.</p>
			<p>Now, proceeding, I'll tell you that reading your letters I got an idea I should like to let you know.</p>
			<p>You speak always of slang as of a special language or dialect, which exists by itself and is spoken only on certain occasions or places and so on. Now, I think, slang is not a diversified language from English as, for instance, Piedmontese is from Tuscan, so that a word, or a phrase, can be told to belong to a class or another.</p>
			<p>You say: this word is slang, and this is classic. But is not slang only the bulk of new English words and expressions continually shaped by living people, as for all languages in all times? I mean, there is not a line to be drawn between the English and the slang words, as two different languages usually spoken by different people and only in certain cases used together.</p>
			<p>That book you know, <title level="m" ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/1542161332348852420009/">Dark Laughter</title>, for instance, is written in English, but there are numberless slang-expressions in it and they are not as French words in an Italian book, but they are a natural part of that language. And I said always English, but I should have said American for I think there is not a slang and a classic language, but there are two diversified languages, the English and the American ones. As slang is the living part of all languages, English has become American by it, that is the two languages have developed themselves separately by means of their respective slangs.</p>
			<p>My conclusion is then that there are not a slang and a classic language but there is an American language formed by a perfectly fused mixture of both.</p>
			<p>Have I succeeded in getting the point before you? Write me something about this also, if you'll have the time.</p>
			<p>Now being in a literary turn I pass to the capital Every word of my opinion on <persName rend="#LewisSinclair"><persName ref="#LewisSinclair">Sinclair Lewis</persName></persName>. Meanwhile you can present my homages to the exceedingly good-minded young lady-friend of yours, first as I like very much young ladies, especially American ones and, second, in order to excuse me if I'll come short of her good opinion which really seems a little flattering and hazarded. However, here I am. I'm sorry to know <persName ref="#LewisSinclair">S. Lewis</persName> only through <title ref="#Babbitt"><title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title></title>. I've so much to do, I've not yet succeeded in getting at least his two other Tauchnitz volumes <title ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Our_Mr._Wrenn">Our Mr Wrenn</title> and <title level="m" ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/186711229/">Arrowsmith</title>. So I'll speak not about <persName ref="#LewisSinclair">S. Lewis</persName>, but about <title ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title>, which in the main I think is the same thing, being almost impossible that a writer as <persName ref="#LewisSinclair">Lewis</persName>, with all his worthes and boundaries, could in a second book have created another world with his accustomed experience of American society.</p>
			<p>At the most he could have changed the class of his hero: instead of a real estate man, a politician or a scientist, but methinks the author's world and point of view would always be the same.</p>
			<p>Now in <title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title>, the first thing which rises one's attention is its lack of plot: not of plot intended as a development of  interesting  facts - a wooing, a murder, etc. (which things indeed there are) - but also the development of a spiritual adventure such as a research, an experience, a conversion, I don't know. Speaking otherwise, what is lacking in <title ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title> is a construction, the building of the harmonious whole, the successive passage onwards where a stage presupposes always, inevitably the lower and the upper one. Whatever episode I read in <title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title> I can almost always enjoy it without knowing before or further. What of this?</p>
			<p>There are many great books of this kind, beginning from <title level="m" ref="#TheMetamorphoses">The Metamorphoses</title> by <persName ref="#Ovid">Ovid</persName> and coming down through the <title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Decameron">Decameron</title> by <persName ref="#GiovanniBoccaccio">Boccaccio</persName> till for instance <title ref="#TheEarthlyParadise">The Earthly Paradise</title> by <persName ref="#WMorris">W. Morris</persName>. But all these books are the aristocratic products of much refined ages when art is absolutely loose from all moral or human cares, and just expresses in its works the poetry which lies in the luxuries of the imagination. The very absence of a progressive plot in them is a hint of this poetry, it is the aristocratic pleasure of the mind fluttering among fine objects, without cares and without end: these gathered fables are all as related by a polite and witty narrator to a selected audience, sometimes (as for the <title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Decameron">Decameron</title> and the <title ref="#TheEaarthlyParadise">Earthly Paradise</title>) this narrator and audience are described just in attitudes of the refined life to which are food these nicely and loosely written pages.</p>
			<p>But as for <title ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title> we are in another world. No more of the poetry of nonchalance and dreamyness, without backbone; this book cannot faultlessly lack a construction, for in its bulk it is the expression of a world which with a smile perceives the hideous clumsyness and deformity especially moral of the inevitable life. So if the story does not contain the drama   sad or merry, it does not matter now - of this clumsyness, which drama could justify, give a successive significance to the facts of the story, this story is doomed to repeat all troughout always the same thing, always presenting a varied scene of life whose purport is always the same clumsyness or whatever else, and each scene lives entirely loose from another.</p>
			<p>For, in <title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title>, the only string is an external one, the daily or monthly existence of <persName ref="#GeorgeFBabbitt">George F. Babbitt</persName> where whatever extraordinary events happen to him, none of them belongs to him save for the fact the author tells us they happen to <persName ref="#GeorgeFBabbitt">G.F. Babbitt</persName>. We find in the first chapters a certain amount of outlines, which presents us already the whole world and spirit intended to be treated all the book long, and there is no further development, this world is a fixed one, or, if we also change people, places, adventures, its spirit is always the same, without a beginning or an end; these pictures could be continued to the infinite. And this same spirit of the book makes it impossible to avoid monotony, differently, as I said, from what happens in those poems of old, where each particular tale is constructed in itself and the harmonious monotony of the whole is a part of their poetry. Sophisticating, one could say this lack of plot is a part of the plot of <title ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title> for its hero has certain hampered whims of romance, and his daily life among belied contradictions and awkward boastings would then be a drama of this barrenness and monotony. But <persName ref="#GeorgeFBabbitt">G. F. Babbitt</persName> does not feel this life as a drama or at least he does not feel it continually with a development of spiritual action which alone could create a construction. There is, true, about the end a continuity and progress of occurrences in <persName ref="#GeorgeFBabbitt">Babbitt</persName>'s rebellion - his love affairs and liking of Seneca Doane and testy and clumsy profession of new principles which ends in nothing or in the childlike repentance of this sad-and-merry puppet, but this does not suffice to create a real plot all the book long. Since hundreds of pages long <persName ref="#LewisSinclair">Lewis</persName> had only presented us a lot, so to say, of lantern slides, the moving picture begins only towards the end, too late to build the novel, so that also this adventure of <persName ref="#GeorgeFBabbitt">Babbitt</persName>'s rebellion restricts itself to the common size of one of the numberless pictures scattered all throughout the book.</p>
			<p>Settled this point about the frame, it remains however to say what then is good in this book so widely read and so indeniably amusing.</p>
			<p>I think <title level="m" ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title> can be well understood only if regarded as a suite of different pieces, each of them pent up in itself, nowhere attaining a climax, or at least each of them beginning, proceeding and concluding by itself alone: too light work to be called a novel and yet so full, so rich, so complete in its way to create by dint of loose short stories, of sketch-dialogues, of draughts, of jokes, etc. a great mythus (as we say today in Italy) of a mankind seen under the point of view of a grotesque matter-of-factness full of the funniest and saddiest inward contrasts between the spoken boastful word and the inmost spirit. But there is no hypocrisy - and here lies the originality of <persName ref="#LewisSinclair">S. Lewis</persName>. Almost all these persons of <title ref="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Babbitt_(novel)">Babbitt</title> are grotesque ones, not villains. They are braggart, petty, coarse and silly, ludicrously in earnest, but outwardly they appear and believe themselves so good-minded, so nice and capital "their city - a city built for giants". And at the bottom, they, G. Babbitt and Paul Riesling at least are so despairingly human and true - their outbursts! And all this world is (as I said) seen only with a curious and amused eye, it has no climax. Since the first page the author has looked at the life and copied thence a piece, careless of developments. In another page he has drawn another picture quite indifferent what the first one were. You could shift the place so fall these episodes without changing the purport of the book. It looks like a book of poetry, a collection of poems written in different cases of the life and huddled together only in order to make a volume.</p>
			<p>But certainly this is no capital fault. We have here huddled together the bulk of numberless little sketches as of a journalist of genius, daily accustomed to put down a column of satirical prose on his contemporaries. Of a journalist Lewis has the great worthes of freshness, spontaneousness and seizing skill, and the little inevitable defects of loose style, minuteness and flippancy sometimes.</p>
			<p>Similarly, the protagonist, Babbitt, has the worth of being wholly created since the first chapter already and the defect of returning in every successive one always the same, without a development, a movement. But he is delightful in this sameness. It would now be too long - and this "opinion" has already the size - of an essay to follow Babbitt in all his doings but certainly, he and all the people of the book are real personages, living in their grotesque world around with so much fitness as to look like a common man living in common life.</p>
			<p>I must then add here that I like Babbitt also for another reason but this not an aesthetic one. It is the most complete picture of contemporary America in its whole character: throughout manners, language, culture, doings, the whole life in short. And this refers itself if not to the piece of art to the powerful mind of Lewis himself, certainly one of your greatest living writers.</p>
			<p>It's done. I hope I should not have mistaken a word for another, smartly succeeding so in getting my ideas all balled up. You'll kindly give me a sincere hint of my lecture here in your next letter. But I should also like, were it possible, to have something written down by the curious young lady-friend of yours, about American literature or whatever else there is of common interest. Would she be interested in it, I should gladly inform her about our modern Italian writers and culture. As for me I would have her speaking about Edgar Lee Masters or Vachel Lindsay whose works also (Spoon River Anthology by the former, and methinks The Congo - The Chinese Nightingale - The Golden Whales of California by the latter) I should pray you to look for, whether there is a cheap edition of them.</p>
			<p>But there are other troubles for you. Would you be so kind as to go fetch them, I should pray you to send me a copy of Waldo Frank's City Block and something of Ernest Hemingway (The Sun Also Rises - Men Without Women - Farewell to the Arms) or whatever else is attainable of him. Especially about the latter there is much talk now here, but no edition of its are seen.</p>
			<p>And still there are scores of modern American books I should like, someone really I need: by J. Dos Passos, by E. Cummings, by W. Carlos Williams, by Countee Cullen, by Eugene O'Neill, by Robinson Jeffers, by Carl Sandburg, by Sherwood Anderson, etc. They are numberless. To buy them by means of an Italian bookseller, there is the danger of finding himself gratified with a cheap edition of five dollars. You see how your christian help is here necessary for me. We ll digest those books little by little, in future letters. Each time one or two among them, and you'll seek for and mail them, together with your bill. Now let us begin with Frank and Hemingway.</p>
			<p>Do you know? I found an American library in Rome very rich with American works such as historical and critical ones. Some classics also as Thoreau and Howells. I'm borrowing two volumes a fortnight by it. But as for modern, living, productions, there is nothing, there is only your help there yonder.</p>
			<p>Accordingly, I send you now the Drolarie by Arnulfi, you wrote about, and   l'ouest rien de nouveau which you are wrong in believing a French book. It is by a German author, as you'll see perusing it, for it is worth while. As I don't know whether you are conversant with German language, I don't send you the German text, nor the Italian translation which does not exist by way of a legal prohibition. It seems that this book has the wrong to describe the war how it is really, an atrocious thing, and naturally we Italian babies are defended to know it by means of a direct translation. We could become too moody and refuse the next war. Mr Chiuminatto, we also wonder how Fascism will fan out.</p>
			<p>But I must leave off. I wind up my yarn with a final thanksgiving for the book you kindly sent me. I'm waiting for it, and I assure you that hardly I'll have received it, by the by, I'll read it notwithstanding my many scholarly occupations and I ll write you something about it.</p>
			<p>And still I beseech you to undergo the expounding of my shameful Babbitt-list only when you'll have nothing else, really nothing else to do. You're so kind I should feel sorry to bother you again.</p>
			<p>Now I'll slip you the accustomed glove and am</p>
			<p>Yours sincerely</p>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>