<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>TITOLO OPERA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Publication Information</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Information about the source</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>Ad Antonio Chiuminatto, Chicago.</p>
			<p>[Torino,] 22 settembre 1930</p>
			<p/>
			<p>My Tony,</p>
			<p>there's only a thing that's worrying me: I cannot make you the proposal to give us the &quot;tu&quot;. 'Twould sound grand and glorious, however, would not it? &quot;O thou who art...&quot; (here I intended to write some extraordinary funny and clever superannuated phrase but darn it, it failed me and I'm here cutting the most deplorable figure).</p>
			<p>Sincerely, our friendship lacks only this to become perfect. I want you to promise me that, would you ever have something to say to me in Italian, you will use the &quot;tu&quot; like you do with Max. I don't know he is prettier or smarter to enjoy such privileges. Now to the point.</p>
			<p>As for Anderson, I knew it was difficult you could succeed. I want you not to worry too much and here I write a note of the comparative importance of them books.</p>
			<p>Mid American Chants. The Triumph of the Egg. Winesburg Ohio. Hello Towns. A New Testament. (They are all on the same degree of importance and not-to-be-done-without. You can buy some of them, also, preferably by second hand). After them come in descending order: Many Marriages. Poor White. Marching Men. Note Books. Tar. The Modern Writer. Windy McPherson's Son. At last, Gertrude Stein's. Vachel Lindsay is another thing: you look after it with leisure and borrow or buy it, we have plenty of time.</p>
			<p>Say, Tony, I'm a fool as sounds a tale by our Anderson in Horses and Men: I wrote &quot;association conditions&quot; without glancing at the dictionary and naturally I was wrong: I intended to say &quot;abbonamento&quot;, &quot;subscription&quot;: I should like to have someday a list of the prices of these magazines (you have the titles) in order to subscribe to some and be so more up to date with your doings. Can you understand, now? I'm very sorry of this unkindness by my part: to write an incomprehensible thing, and I assure you I'll henceforward be more careful.</p>
			<p>Thanks to you for your happy intentions about slang. I'll be hanged if I am not owing to you my whole learning. Someday I'll try to reciprocate.</p>
			<p>I called on Misses Franchi: they said me a lot of kind things about you and offered me a protector in America: whom I don't as yet want, as my dealings with Columbia are as yet unfinished and, at least, for this winter, I think there will be nothing new.</p>
			<p>But. Patience is also a virtue.</p>
			<p>Say, old socks, Max tells me you are unsatisfied with your America. How comes? I know that one's country is always more captivating when abroad, but you must not forget that coming abroad is also intended to augment one's understanding of the native country. And you, who are in the tremendous situation of being both an Italian and an American, you must try to comprehend the two nations, try to raise above the petty difficulties. Moreover you must not forget that we Italians are two distinct nations, the North and the South, and that we are the Northern and that the Chicagoans gunmen are the Southern and there is a deeper difference of race and history between us and them that nothing could repair.</p>
			<p>As for the money-making America think that all great nations were in the beginning money-makers, also Italy, when in the twelfth century a bunch of republics, and look in Anderson and Lewis for an escape from that.</p>
			<p>Lewis will teach you how to understand and love the money-makers, the Americans, how to love them across irony, across that human tenderness which comes out from artistic contemplation: after all, the Americans of Lewis are good, very good people, and dear, also, in their somewhat childish psychology. And you've seen in Arrowsmith how this childishness can become in a nothing a true human and brotherly suffering.</p>
			<p>And in Anderson you find your own problem uttered: Americans are money-makers, they cannot be artists or such: but you see in the very person of the author that artists can after all be born in U.S.A. and create a new art, which comes directly from your new life: factories, humble people, tortured intellectuals, or artists themselves. You know: Anderson is somehow an Italian like you: his grandmother was Italian. You must think of this: you are middlewestern like your greatest contemporary writers (and not only money-makers), you are a son of two races and so you can enjoy the odds of both: don't turn out a piker, a traitor, a four-flusher, an outlaw of the culture.</p>
			<p>I expect something by you about this. Now good-bye and a manly wallop by your Buddy.</p>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
