<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>TITOLO OPERA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Publication Information</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Information about the source</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>Ad Antonio Chiuminatto, Green Bay, Wisconsin.</p>
			<p>[Torino,] April the 17th, 1930</p>
			<p/>
			<p>Dear Tony,</p>
			<p>I have at last succeeded! Photographers are worse than tailors. Here's my close-up, all for you.</p>
			<p>On this same day I'll try to pack back the Kellog's books. You see, in fifteen days I've got through.</p>
			<p>Am I not right on the job? In order you don't think I've only turned over their leaves, I'll give you a snappy critical sketch on each. Don't shudder: it's like the dentist.</p>
			<p>Best of all is surely Roan Stallion. Say, Mr Chiuminatto, there in America you've got poets as flies in summer. Not only you have your well-known wonderful jazz-minstrels, but, what's more, a lot of other poets whose existence is entirely unsuspected here in Europe. There are a few wits here acquainted with and they seem to like the secret. This Mr Robinson Jeffers threatens to become another Whitman of yours, with his eagle's glance from California, as the other fellow for Long Island. His idylls of the coast-range (Roan Stallion, Tamar, Fauna, etc.) are all things that let people staring around. Their simple background of not affected rough life (especially in R[oan] S[tallion]) which in a blink soars in the highest lyrical heaven involving a whole vision of history and America is something worth reading. I'm too warm with it already to give a sure criticism about, but I'll keep an eye on this writer and come back to him.</p>
			<p>Meanwhile, what's wonderful, he also is a Midwesterner almost, by birth. You are filling the American Literature with Midwestern geniuses: Lee Masters from Kansas, Dreiser from Indiana, Lewis from Minnesota, Anderson from Ohio, Hemingway and Sandburg from Illinois, Wescott from Wisconsin: you've got to be new New England. Smart fellow also that E. Hemingway. I keep yet untouched the Farewell, which I never find time to read, but as for The Sun also rises I went through and found it an extraordinary piece of description of our own generation. The freshness of it, almost its candidness in the utterance of the riskier and more complicated things of our mentality is unmatched.</p>
			<p>And as for Wescott I must repeat that it would be of unvaluable opportunity here in Italy where everybody keeps the wrong ideas about you American people. It would show the deep roots and earnestness of your nationality and teach someone to regard, with another consideration that the wealth's, your rising importance. There are the stories of Great-Aunt Mary and Uncle Evan especially which beat everything. You must read this book.</p>
			<p>Say, Mr Chiuminatto, apropos of Hemingway would you kindly explain me if Sun also rises means &quot;anche il sole si leva&quot; or &quot;il sole si leva anche&quot;? It's a difficult stuff this of adverbs in English.</p>
			<p>I'm yet wondering what happened to your Cabell - Dos Passos - and - Sandburg package: you say you mailed it on the same day with the other books wrote about, but as yet I rec'd only the aforesaid ones. Would the whole have shipwrecked? This reminds me that you have not yet spoken about the Arnulfi-Remarque mailing. I hope they have not gone to the Devil as I fear mine have. However write me.</p>
			<p>Now, thank you, and keep smiling contemplating yours</p>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
