<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>TITOLO OPERA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Publication Information</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Information about the source</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>Ad Antonio Chiuminatto, Chicago.</p>
			<p>[Torino,] 2nd Apr. '32</p>
			<p/>
			<p>At last I'm here answering you. As for Faulkner you're right: he's a tremendous bore, till now at least: I didn't as yet get through the whole book. I buy it however as a curiosity and enclose here the dough. I cannot remember whether I'm yet owing you something: please look over your accounts-books and send me a notice.</p>
			<p>As for that proposition you offer me of borrowing books for a month, I don't think it available. It'd be too much trouble for you to pack and hand over like lightning, and it'd necessitate from my part, in order to get in time, more time than I can find. It'd mean expenses, perhaps you'll wreak your own Chicagoan Reputation, no more returning some books… no, it's better to buy sometime someone.</p>
			<p>Thank you for the explanation you put down for me: it was very useful. So you're not forgetting old ways?</p>
			<p>Say, just this evening I'm swept along by the wanderlust. I swear here to you that I cannot any more stay here in Italy. My army-duty is over at last. I've no news of my old fixing with Columbia, and don't speak about blues, boy! I dream, hope, long, die after America. I must come.</p>
			<p>Till now you've been so kind with me: try to make me the last and greatest favor, call me in USA. You know, we cannot come over without an employment from over there. It's now your task of friendship to find me an employment, however a nominal one, something to get the passport. I'm ready to teach Italian or to marry the horridest heiress, only I could get there.</p>
			<p>Apply to the University, whether there are possibilities to find a place as an assistant, as an usher, as a what-you-call-it. Only, help me through. Otherwise I'll try revolution in Mexico and bootlegging through the frontier.</p>
			<p>Now that I've cooled myself out let us speak of records. Yours consels are very precious but nothing of what you point at in your list is found here in Italy.</p>
			<p>But avast... I hope I'll buy my next records right there in God's Country.</p>
			<p>On any day - even to-morrow, I'm ready to pack. Only say the word, boy!</p>
			<p>Pav.</p>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
