<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>TITOLO OPERA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Publication Information</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Information about the source</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>Ad <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/120757469/" type="real">Antonio Chiuminatto</persName>, <placeName ref="https://geonames.org/4887398" type="real">Chicago</placeName>.</p>
			<p>[Torino,] 26 marzo [1931]</p>
			<p/>
			<p>Dear <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/120757469/" type="real">Old Tony</persName>,</p>
			<p>I want to thank you infinitely for your swell results about my journalistic career. You bet you are a Live-Wire! Now listen, I'm enormously glad to be given a chance in USA, with the hope to enlarge subsequently my field. Moreover, I think, American review-world is not like ours so divided in quarreling groups and it is possible to appear in a sheet without dyeing oneself with the color of this same sheet. I say so, with an eye to the religious tinge Thought certainly has got and my essay certainly hasn't.</p>
			<p>So I'll begin to put down a new essay on Lewis. There's also another reason to rewrite the old one, apart from the rule of "Thought", and that's this: I've got to speak to an American public, no more to Italians. And this changes things a little. I don't promise you the new article for too soon, as you know I'm already breaking myself down with work, but certainly in the month of April, it'll be done.</p>
			<p>Now, I want only to congratulate you and arrange businesses. If some mazooma will come out of our united literary strivings, that is, if Thought will send you some doremi, we'll go fifty-fifty. Are you game?</p>
			<p>Say, Buddy, in a fortnight, my Anderson will appear!</p>
			<p>Take your time, as for Shylock and A Jew in Love. And more time take about summer books. Perhaps I'll already be over there, by that time. In April I'll know the sentence.</p>
			<p>I'm glad to hear from you good news about the fiddle - mightly glad. And so you also are hanging on, eh! Well, we'll yet turn out the Phenomenical Twins, what d'you say?</p>
			<p>Now, I beg many - too many - pardons, and must come back to my unrelenting works.</p>
			<p>So keep an eye on Father Parsons and you'll soon get the stuff.</p>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>